Preliminary Guide to the Philosophy Department records, 1904-1996 RG0076
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Philosophy Department records
1904-1996
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Dept. of Philosophy
RG0076
1.75 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include syllabus, postcards, flyers, news bulletin, and press releases. They range in date from 1904-96. The materials concern lectures, "Techne", and the Elton lecture. There are also a number of folders for the Washington Philosophy Club.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Acquisition information for this collection is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
During the freshman and sophomore years, studies included English, Latin, and Greek; geography; arithmetic and algebra; history and antiquities; exercises in reading, speaking and composition; elements of chronology; rhetoric and logic; logarithms, geometry, trigonometry and mensuration; surveying, navigation, conic sections and Euclid's Elements. In his junior and senior years, the student took natural philosophy, astronomy, chemistry, fluxions, natural history, history of civil society, natural religion, Revelation, natural and political law, metaphysics, moral philosophy and analogy of religion to nature. Today the Philosophy Department is a part of the Columbian College of Arts and Sciences. This note was written in 2005.
bib #
9063047
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include syllabus, postcards, flyers, news bulletin, and press releases. They range in date from 1904-96. The materials concern lectures, "Techne", and the Elton lecture.
Formerly RG9.21
General
Box two contains the files of Proessor Peter Caws, university professor of philosophy. He was elected the president of the Washington Philosophy Club in 1988.
Washington (D.C.); Lectures and lecturing; George Washington University
- Philosophy Department, 1904-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Philosophy Department - Elton Lectures, 02/24/1965-02/23/1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Washington Philosophy Club (WPC), 1974-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Washington Philosophy Club files, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  General
  President: Diane F. Gottlieb
- WPC program planning, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3-6)
- WPC program correspondence and planning, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7-10)
- Professor Caws syllabi - Peace Studies, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Philosophy department records, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- WPC programming and correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- WPC newsletters, 1956-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
- WPC program planning and correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
- Peace studies, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)